econbiz.de 2017-06-06

# Privacy: EconBizPortal

It is important to us to protect your privacy when using our websites, so we would like to ask you to please note the following information:

##  etracker

This website uses etracker technology (www.etracker.com) to collect data on visitor behavior. The data is collected anonymously for optimization of our services. All visitor data is saved using an anonymous user ID and can be used to aggregate a usage profile. The data collected by the etracker technology will not be used to determine the personal identity of a website visitor. 

etracker claims that all its solutions are 100% conform with data protection laws.

## Cookies

In order to provide better functionality we use so-called "cookies". These "cookies" allow files to be saved on your computer when you access our website. You can disallow the saving of cookies on your PC by changing the settings of your internet browser. However, this will reduce the range of services available to you.

## Anonymous Data Collection

As a matter of principle, you can visit the EconBiz website without informing us who you are. We only get to know the name of your internet service provider, the website from which you came to our website and which of our websites you visit. This information will be evaluated for statistical purposes. You as an individual user remain anonymous.

## Collection and Processing of Personal Data

If there is an option to enter personal or business data (e-mail addresses, names, addresses) on the website, the user will disclose such information on a voluntary basis only. Personal data are only collected if you submit them voluntarily.

## Utilisation and Circulation of Personal Data

The personal data collected through the EconBiz websites will only be used without your consent for the execution of contracts and in order to process your enquiries. If you have previously provided your consent, your data shall also be used for the purposes of providing information on our products and services, conducting market research, and tailoring our electronic services to meet your requirements. Equally, your data shall only be used for tailoring information to your personal requirements if you have granted your consent. Your data will not be circulated to third parties. You can of course revoke your consent at any time, effective from the time of revocation.

## Transfer and Processing of Data to Countries outside the European Economic Area

We do not transfer any of these data into states outside the EEA. This excludes personal data you provide in the webforms sent to Research Guide EconDesk. This data transfer is performed on the basis of the "standard contractual clauses for the transfer of personal data to third countries" of the European Union. Please be aware that the level of data protection in third countries might differ from German and EU standards. 

## External Links

In EconBiz you will find links to third parties’ websites. EconBiz cannot control the contents and design of these third parties’ websites. Therefore, the guarantees given by this data protection statement do of course not apply to these websites.
